Speaking up is hard to do.
من الصعب التحدث.
I understood the true meaning of this phrase exactly one month ago,
استوعبت معنى هذه العبارة الحقيقي قبل شهر بالضبط
when my wife and I became new parents.
عندما أصبحنا أنا وزوجتي والدين جدد.
It was an amazing moment.
لقد كانت لحظة مدهشة.
It was exhilarating and elating,
لقد كانت لحظة مُنعشة ومُنتشية.
but it was also scary and terrifying.
ولكنها كانت مُخيفة ومُرعبة كذلك.
And it got particularly terrifying when we got home from the hospital,
وأَصبحت مُرعبة خاصةً عندما وصلنا إلى المنزل من المستشفى،
and we were unsure
كنا غير متأكدين
whether our little baby boy was getting enough nutrients from breastfeeding.
ما إذا كان يحصل طفلنا الصغير على عناصر غذائية كافية من الرضاعة الطبيعية.
And we wanted to call our pediatrician,
أردنا أن نتصل بطبيبة الأطفال،
but we also didn't want to make a bad first impression
ولكن لم نريد أن يكون لنا إنطباع أولي سيء،
or come across as a crazy, neurotic parent.
أو نكون كوالدان مجنونان ومتعصّبان.
So we worried.
لذا قلقنا.
And we waited.
وانتظرنا.
When we got to the doctor's office the next day,
عندما ذهبنا إلى مكتب الطبيبة في اليوم التالي،
she immediately gave him formula because he was pretty dehydrated.
أعطته وصفة طبية فوراً؛ لأنه كان يعاني من القليل من الجفاف.
Our son is fine now,
ابننا بخير الآن،
and our doctor has reassured us we can always contact her.
وطمأنتنا طبيبتنا بأننا نستطيع الإتصال بها دائماً.
But in that moment,
ولكن في تلك اللحظة،
I should've spoken up, but I didn't.
كان يجب علي أن أتحدث ولكنني لم أفعل.
But sometimes we speak up when we shouldn't,
لكننا أحياناً نتحدث عندما لا ينبغي علينا أن نتحدث،
and I learned that over 10 years ago when I let my twin brother down.
حيث تعلمت ذلك عندما خَذلتُ أخي التوأم منذ أكثر من ١٠ سنوات.
My twin brother is a documentary filmmaker,
أخي التوأم مُخرج أفلام وثائقية،
and for one of his first films,
وحصل على عرض من شركة توزيع
he got an offer from a distribution company.
لأحدى أول أفلامه.
He was excited,
لقد كان متحمساً،
and he was inclined to accept the offer.
وكان مُستعداً إلى قبول العرض
But as a negotiations researcher,
ولكنني أصررت عليه كباحث في المفاوضات
I insisted he make a counteroffer,
أن يجري عرضاً مضاداً،
and I helped him craft the perfect one.
وساعدته في صُنع واحدة مثالية.
And it was perfect --
لقد كان مثالياً.
it was perfectly insulting.
كان مهين بشكل مثالي.
The company was so offended,
استائت الشركة جداً،
they literally withdrew the offer
وسحبت عرضها حرفياً،
and my brother was left with nothing.
وتُرك أخي بأيدٍ خاوية.
And I've asked people all over the world about this dilemma of speaking up:
سألت أناس من جميع أنحاء العالم عن معضلة التحدث هذه:
when they can assert themselves,
عندما يمكنهم فرض أنفسهم،
when they can push their interests,
عندما يمكنهم شق طريقهم نحو اهتماماتهم،
when they can express an opinion,
عندما يمكنهم التعبير عن آرائهم،
when they can make an ambitious ask.
عندما يمكنهم طرح سؤالٍ طَموح.
And the range of stories are varied and diverse,
ونطاق القصص متنوع ومختلف،
but they also make up a universal tapestry.
لكنها أيضاً تصنع نسيج عالمي.
Can I correct my boss when they make a mistake?
هل يمكنني أن أصحح رئيسي عندما يخطيء؟
Can I confront my coworker who keeps stepping on my toes?
هل يمكنني التصدي لزميلي الذي يتدخل بعملي؟
Can I challenge my friend's insensitive joke?
هل يمكنني تحدي نكتة صديقي الغير مراعية للمشاعر؟
Can I tell the person I love the most my deepest insecurities?
هل يمكنني أن أخبر الشخص الذي أحبه عن قلقي العميق؟
And through these experiences, I've come to recognize
أصبحت أُدرك من خلال هذه التجارب
that each of us have something called a range of acceptable behavior.
أن كل شخص منا لديه ما يسمى نطاق السلوك المقبول.
Now, sometimes we're too strong; we push ourselves too much.
بعض الأحيان نكون أقوياء جداً؛ فندفع أنفسنا أكثر مما ينبغي.
That's what happened with my brother.
وهذا ما حدث مع أخي.
Even making an offer was outside his range of acceptable behavior.
حتى أن القبول بالعرض كان خارج نطاق سلوكه المقبول.
But sometimes we're too weak.
ولكننا ضعفاء جداً بعض الأحيان.
That's what happened with my wife and I.
وهذا ماحدث معي أنا وزوجتي.
And this range of acceptable behaviors --
فنطاق السلوك المقبول هذا
when we stay within our range, we're rewarded.
يجعلنا نُكافأ عندما نبقى ضمن حدود نطاقنا.
When we step outside that range, we get punished in a variety of ways.
ونُعاقب بطرق متنوعة عندما نخرج خارج نطاقنا.
We get dismissed or demeaned or even ostracized.
إما أن نُطرد أو نُهان أو نُنبذ أيضاً.
Or we lose that raise or that promotion or that deal.
أو نفقد ذلك الارتقاء أو ذلك الترويج أو تلك الصفقة.
Now, the first thing we need to know is:
أول شيء يجب علينا معرفته هو:
What is my range?
ماهو نطاقي؟
But the key thing is, our range isn't fixed;
ولكن النقطة الرئيسية هي أن نطاقنا غير ثابت،
it's actually pretty dynamic.
ولكنه في الحقيقة حركي قليلاً.
It expands and it narrows based on the context.
ولكنه يتوسع ويضيق على حسب السياق.
And there's one thing that determines that range more than anything else,
يوجد شيء واحد يحدد ذلك النطاق أكثر من غيره،
and that's your power.
وذلك هو طاقتك.
Your power determines your range.
تحدد طاقتك نطاقك.
What is power?
ماهي الطاقة؟
Power comes in lots of forms.
تأتي الطاقة بأشكال عدة.
In negotiations, it comes in the form of alternatives.
فهي تأتي على شكل بدائل في المفاوضات.
So my brother had no alternatives;
لذا لا توجد لدى أخي بدائل؛
he lacked power.
فهو تنقصه الطاقة.
The company had lots of alternatives;
لدى الشركة كثير من البدائل؛
they had power.
فهم لديهم طاقة.
Sometimes it's being new to a country, like an immigrant,
بعض الأحيان تكون شيء جديد على بلد، مثل المهاجر،
or new to an organization
أو جديدة على منظمة،
or new to an experience,
أو جديدة على تجربة،
like my wife and I as new parents.
مثلي أنا وزوجتي كوالدين جدد.
Sometimes it's at work,
بعض الأحيان تكون في العمل،
where someone's the boss and someone's the subordinate.
حيث يكون شخص ما رئيس والآخر مرؤوس.
Sometimes it's in relationships,
بعض الأحيان تكون في العلاقات،
where one person's more invested than the other person.
حيث يكون أحد الأشخاص مُكرّس نفسه أكثر من الآخر.
And the key thing is that when we have lots of power,
النقطة الرئيسية هي سيكون نطاقنا واسع جداً
our range is very wide.
عندما تكون لدينا الكثير من الطاقة.
We have a lot of leeway in how to behave.
لدينا الكثير من الحرية في سلوكنا.
But when we lack power, our range narrows.
لكن يضيق نطاقنا عندما تنقصنا الطاقة.
We have very little leeway.
لدينا حرية قليلة للغاية.
The problem is that when our range narrows,
المشكلة هي عندما يضيق نطاقنا ينتج شيء يسمى
that produces something called the low-power double bind.
بقيد مزدوج منخفض الطاقة.
The low-power double bind happens
يحدث القيد المزدوج منخفض الطاقة
when, if we don't speak up, we go unnoticed,
عندما لا نتحدث فإننا لا نُلاحَظ،
but if we do speak up, we get punished.
لكننا إذا تحدثنا نُعاقب.
Now, many of you have heard the phrase the "double bind"
سمع العديد منكم بعبارة "القيد المزدوج"،
and connected it with one thing, and that's gender.
وربطها مع شيء واحد ألا وهو نوع الجنس.
The gender double bind is women who don't speak up go unnoticed,
القيد المزدوج لنوع الجنس هو النساء اللاتي لا يتحدثن لا يُلاحَظن،
and women who do speak up get punished.
والنساء اللاتي يتحدثن يُعاقبن.
And the key thing is that women have the same need as men to speak up,
النقطة الرئيسية هي أن للنساء احتياجات للتحدث كما للرجال،
but they have barriers to doing so.
ولكنهن لديهن حواجز تحولهن عن ذلك.
But what my research has shown over the last two decades
لكن ما أظهره بحثي على مدى العقدين الماضيين،
is that what looks like a gender difference
أن ما يبدو أنه كفرق بنوع الجنس
is not really a gender double bind,
فهو ليس بقيد مزدوج لنوع الجنس بالفعل،
it's a really a low-power double bind.
وإنما هو قيد مزدوج منخفض الطاقة.
And what looks like a gender difference
وغالباً أن ما يبدو أنه كاختلاف بنوع الجنس
are really often just power differences in disguise.
يكون مجرد اختلافات بالطاقة متخفّية.
Oftentimes we see a difference between a man and a woman
كثيراً ما نرى اختلافاً بين رجل وامرأة،
or men and women,
أو رجال ونساء،
and think, "Biological cause. There's something fundamentally different
ونعتقد "أن السبب بيولوجي. أنه يوجد شيء مختلف جذرياً
about the sexes."
حول الجنسين"
But in study after study,
ولكني وجدت في دراسة بعد دراسة،
I've found that a better explanation for many sex differences
أن التوضيح الأفضل للعديد من الاختلافات بين الجنسين
is really power.
هي الطاقة بالفعل.
And so it's the low-power double bind.
وذلك هو قيد مزدوج منخفض الطاقة.
And the low-power double bind means that we have a narrow range,
ويعني القيد المزدوج منخفض الطاقة أن لدينا نطاق ضيق،
and we lack power.
وأننا تنقصنا الطاقة.
We have a narrow range,
لدينا نطاق ضيق،
and our double bind is very large.
وقيدنا المزدوج كبير جداً.
So we need to find ways to expand our range.
لذا يجب علينا إيجاد طرق لتوسيع نطاقنا.
And over the last couple decades,
حيث وجدت أنا وزملائي
my colleagues and I have found two things really matter.
أمرين مهمين جداً على مدى العقود القليلة الماضية.
The first: you seem powerful in your own eyes.
الأول: أن تبدو قوياً بنظر نفسك.
The second: you seem powerful in the eyes of others.
الثاني: أن تبدو قوياً في نظر الآخرين.
When I feel powerful,
عندما أشعر بالقوة،
I feel confident, not fearful;
فإنني أشعر بالثقة، وليس بالخوف؛
I expand my own range.
وبذلك أوسّع نطاقي.
When other people see me as powerful,
عندما يراني الآخرون قوياً،
they grant me a wider range.
فإنهم يمنحوني نطاقاً أوسع.
So we need tools to expand our range of acceptable behavior.
لذا نحن نحتاج أدوات لتوسيع نطاق سلوكنا المقبول.
And I'm going to give you a set of tools today.
سأعطيكم اليوم مجموعة من الأدوات.
Speaking up is risky,
التحدث محفوف بالمخاطر،
but these tools will lower your risk of speaking up.
لكن هذه الأدوات ستُخفّض مُخاطرة التحدث عنك.
The first tool I'm going to give you got discovered in negotiations
اُكتشِفت الأداة الأولى التي سأعطيكم في المفاوضات
in an important finding.
في اكتشافٍ مهم.
On average, women make less ambitious offers
يتخذن النساء مساعي لطموحاتٍ أقل،
and get worse outcomes than men at the bargaining table.
ويحصلن على نتائج سيئة في المتوسط على طاولة المفاوضات مقارنةً بالرجال .
But Hannah Riley Bowles and Emily Amanatullah have discovered
ولكن اكتشفت كل من هانا رايلي وإيميلي أمانة الله
there's one situation where women get the same outcomes as men
أنه يوجد حل واحد لحصول النساء على نتائج مساوية للرجال،
and are just as ambitious.
ومتساوية بالطموح.
That's when they advocate for others.
وذلك عندما يدافعن عن الآخرين.
When they advocate for others,
فهن يكتشفن نطاقهن الخاص بهن
they discover their own range and expand it in their own mind.
ويوسعنَه في عقولهن عندما يدافعن عن الآخرين.
They become more assertive.
حيث يصبحون أكثر جزماً.
This is sometimes called "the mama bear effect."
وهذا ما يسمى أحيناناً بـ: "تأثير أم الدب".
Like a mama bear defending her cubs,
وذلك مثل دفاع أم الدب عن صغارها،
when we advocate for others, we can discover our own voice.
فعندما ندافع عن الآخرين، نستطيع اكتشاف أصواتنا.
But sometimes, we have to advocate for ourselves.
ولكن يجب علينا الدفاع عن أنفسنا بعض الأحيان.
How do we do that?
كيف نقوم بذلك؟
One of the most important tools we have to advocate for ourselves
أحد الأدوات المهمة جداً عندنا للدفاع عن أنفسنا
is something called perspective-taking.
شيء يسمى بتبني وجهة النظر.
And perspective-taking is really simple:
تبني وجهة النظر بسيطٌ جداً:
it's simply looking at the world through the eyes of another person.
فهو ببساطة النظر إلى العالم بأعين شخص آخر.
It's one of the most important tools we have to expand our range.
وهي أحد الأدوات الهامة جداً لدينا لتوسيع نطاقنا.
When I take your perspective,
عندما أتبنى وجهة نظرك،
and I think about what you really want,
وأفكر فيما تريد فعلاً،
you're more likely to give me what I really want.
من المرجح أن تعطيني ما أريده بالفعل.
But here's the problem:
ولكن المشكلة هي:
perspective-taking is hard to do.
أنه من الصعب تبني وجهة النظر.
So let's do a little experiment.
لذا فالنقم بتجربة بسيطة.
I want you all to hold your hand just like this:
أريدكم أن تمسكوا أيديكم هكذا:
your finger -- put it up.
ارفعوا إصابعكم إلى الأعلى.
And I want you to draw a capital letter E on your forehead
وأريدكم أن ترسموا حرف الـ E على جباهكم
as quickly as possible.
بأسرع مايمكن.
OK, it turns out that we can draw this E in one of two ways,
حسناً، تبيّن أننا نستطيع رسم حرف الـE بأحدى طريقتين،
and this was originally designed as a test of perspective-taking.
وكان هذا مصمماً بالأصل كاختبار لتبني وجهة النظر.
I'm going to show you two pictures
سأريكم صورتين
of someone with an E on their forehead --
لشخص لديه E على جبهته،
my former student, Erika Hall.
وهي إيريكا هال تلميذتي السابقة.
And you can see over here,
يمكنكم أن تروا هنا،
that's the correct E.
بأنها الـE الصحيحة.
I drew the E so it looks like an E to another person.
لقد رسمت الـE لتبدوا كـE لشخص آخر.
That's the perspective-taking E
هذا هو تبني وجهة النظر للـE؛
because it looks like an E from someone else's vantage point.
لأنها تبدو كـE من وجهة نظر شخص آخر.
But this E over here is the self-focused E.
ولكن هذه الـE هنا هي الـE المُركّزة على الذات.
We often get self-focused.
غالباً ما نركز على الذات.
And we particularly get self-focused in a crisis.
ونركز على الذات خاصةً في الأزمات.
I want to tell you about a particular crisis.
أريد إخباركم عن أزمة معينة.
A man walks into a bank in Watsonville, California.
رجل يدخل إلى بنك في واتسونفيل بكاليفورنيا،
And he says, "Give me $2,000,
ويقول: "أعطني ٢٠٠٠ دولار،
or I'm blowing the whole bank up with a bomb."
وإلا سأفجر البنك بأكمله بقنبلة".
Now, the bank manager didn't give him the money.
مديرة البنك لم تعطهِ المال.
She took a step back.
أخذت خطوة للخلف.
She took his perspective,
فقد تبنّت وجهة نظره،
and she noticed something really important.
ولاحظت شيئاً مهماً جداً.
He asked for a specific amount of money.
بأنه سأل عن مبلغ معين من المال.
So she said,
فقالت له:
"Why did you ask for $2,000?"
"لماذا طلبت ٢٠٠٠ دولار؟".
And he said, "My friend is going to be evicted
فقال: " صديقي سيُطرد
unless I get him $2,000 immediately."
مالم أحصل له على ٢٠٠٠ دولار حالاً".
And she said, "Oh! You don't want to rob the bank --
فقالت: "إذاً لا ينبغي عليك سرقة البنك،
you want to take out a loan."
يجب عليك أخذ قرض"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
"Why don't you come back to my office,
"لما لا تأتي إلى مكتبي،
and we can have you fill out the paperwork."
لتعبيء بعض الأوراق".
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Now, her quick perspective-taking defused a volatile situation.
إذاً أبطل تبنيها السريع لوجهة النظر وضعاً متقلباً.
So when we take someone's perspective,
لذا عندما نتبنى وجهة نظر شخص آخر،
it allows us to be ambitious and assertive, but still be likable.
يتيح لنا أن نكون طموحين وجازمين وفي نفس الوقت محبوبين.
Here's another way to be assertive but still be likable,
وهنا طريقة أخرى لنكون جازمين وفي نفس الوقت محبوبين،
and that is to signal flexibility.
وذلك للإشارة إلى المرونة.
Now, imagine you're a car salesperson, and you want to sell someone a car.
تخيل أنك بائع سيارات، وتريد أن تبيع سيارة لشخص ما.
You're going to more likely make the sale if you give them two options.
ستبيع السيارة على الأرجح إذا أعطيته خيارين.
Let's say option A:
فالنقل الخيار أ:
$24,000 for this car and a five-year warranty.
ثمنها ٢٤٠٠٠ دولار مع ضمان خمس سنوات.
Or option B:
أو الخيار ب:
$23,000 and a three-year warranty.
ثمنها ٢٣٠٠٠ دولار مع ضمان ثلاث سنوات.
My research shows that when you give people a choice among options,
يُظهر بحثي أنه عندما تعطي الناس خياراً ضمن خيارات،
it lowers their defenses,
يقلل ذلك من دفاعاتهم،
and they're more likely to accept your offer.
ويكونون أكثر قبولاً لعرضك.
And this doesn't just work with salespeople;
وهذا لا ينجح مع البائعين فقط؛
it works with parents.
ولكنه ينجح مع الوالدين.
When my niece was four,
عارضت ابنة أخي ارتداء ملابسها
she resisted getting dressed and rejected everything.
ورفضت كل شيء عندما كانت في الرابعة من العمر.
But then my sister-in-law had a brilliant idea.
ولكن كان لدى زوجة أخي فكرة رائعة.
What if I gave my daughter a choice?
ماذا لو أعطيت ابنتي خَيار؟
This shirt or that shirt? OK, that shirt.
هذا القميص أم ذلك القميص؟ حسناً، ذلك القميص.
This pant or that pant? OK, that pant.
هذا البنطلون أم ذلك البنطلون؟ حسناً، ذلك البنطلون.
And it worked brilliantly.
نجحت هذه الطريقة ببراعة.
She got dressed quickly and without resistance.
لبست بسرعة وبدون معارضة.
When I've asked the question around the world
عندما كنت أطرح هذا السؤال حول العالم:
when people feel comfortable speaking up,
متى يشعر الناس بالراحة ليتحدثون؟
the number one answer is:
الإجابة رقم واحد كانت:
"When I have social support in my audience; when I have allies."
"عندما يكون لدي دعم اجتماعي من جمهوري؛ أي عندما يكون لدي حلفاء"
So we want to get allies on our side.
لذا نريد أن نحصل على حلفاء إلى جانبنا.
How do we do that?
كيف نقوم بذلك؟
Well, one of the ways is be a mama bear.
أحد الطرق هي أن تصبح أم دب.
When we advocate for others,
عندما ندافع عن الآخرين،
we expand our range in our own eyes and the eyes of others,
فإننا نوسع نطاقنا في أعيننا وأعين الآخرين،
but we also earn strong allies.
ولكننا نكسب حلفاء أقوياء في الوقت ذاته.
Another way we can earn strong allies, especially in high places,
الطريقة الأخرى لكسب حلفاء أقوياء، وخصوصاً في الأماكن الراقية،
is by asking other people for advice.
هي بطلب النصيحة من الناس.
When we ask others for advice, they like us because we flatter them,
عندما نطلب من الآخرين النصيحة، سيحبوننا لأننا نتملق لهم،
and we're expressing humility.
ونحن نتعامل معهم بتواضع.
And this really works to solve another double bind.
وينجح هذا لحل قيد مزدوج آخر.
And that's the self-promotion double bind.
وذلك هو قيد مزدوج ذاتي الترويج.
The self-promotion double bind
القيد المزدوج ذاتي الترويج
is that if we don't advertise our accomplishments,
هو إذا لم نعلن عن إنجازاتنا،
no one notices.
لا يلاحظها أحد.
And if we do, we're not likable.
وإذا فعلنا ذلك فنحن لسنا محبوبين.
But if we ask for advice about one of our accomplishments,
ولكن إذا طلبنا النصيحة لأحد إنجازاتنا،
we are able to be competent in their eyes but also be likeable.
فنحن قادرون على أن نكون كفوئين بأعينهم ومحبوبين كذلك.
And this is so powerful
هذا قوي جداً،
it even works when you see it coming.
وهذا ينجح عندما تراه يقترب.
There have been multiple times in life when I have been forewarned
حُذِّرت عدة مرات في حياتي
that a low-power person has been given the advice to come ask me for advice.
بأن الشخص منخفض الطاقة نُصِحَ بأن يطلب النصيحة مني.
I want you to notice three things about this:
أريدك أن تلاحظ ثلاثة أشياء عن هذا:
First, I knew they were going to come ask me for advice.
الأول، كنت أعلم أنهم سيطلبون مني النصيحة.
Two, I've actually done research on the strategic benefits
الثاني، أنني في الحقيقة قمت بعمل بحث عن الفوائد التخطيطية
of asking for advice.
لطلب النصيحة.
And three, it still worked!
والثالث، أنها ما زالت ناجحة!
I took their perspective,
تبنيتُ وجهة نظرهم،
I became more invested in their cause,
وأصبحت مكرّس نفسي لندائاتهم بشكل أكثر،
I became more committed to them because they asked for advice.
أصبحت ملتزماً لهم بشكل أكثر لأنهم يطلبون مني النصيحة.
Now, another time we feel more confident speaking up
المرة الأخرى التي سنشعر بها بالثقة للتحدث
is when we have expertise.
هي عندما تكون لدينا المهارة.
Expertise gives us credibility.
المهارة تعطينا المصداقية.
When we have high power, we already have credibility.
عندما تكون لدينا طاقة عالية، فستكون لدينا المصداقية بالفعل.
We only need good evidence.
فنحن نريد براهين جيدة فقط.
When we lack power, we don't have the credibility.
عندما تنقصنا الطاقة فلن تكون لدينا المصداقية.
We need excellent evidence.
فنحن نريد براهين ممتازة.
And one of the ways we can come across as an expert
أحد الطرق التي يمكننا أن نتطرق لها كخبراء
is by tapping into our passion.
هي بالاستفادة من شغفنا.
I want everyone in the next few days to go up to friend of theirs
أريد من الجميع أن يذهبوا إلى أحد أصدقائهم في الأيام القليلة المقبلة
and just say to them,
ويقولوا لهم:
"I want you to describe a passion of yours to me."
"أريدك أن تصف لي شغفٌ خاصٌ بك".
I've had people do this all over the world
لدي أناس يقومون بذلك حول العالم،
and I asked them,
وسألتهم:
"What did you notice about the other person
"ماذا لاحظتم على الأشخاص الآخرين
when they described their passion?"
عندما وصفوا شغفهم؟".
And the answers are always the same.
والأجوبة هي نفسها دائماً.
"Their eyes lit up and got big."
"أعينهم اشتعلت وكبرت".
"They smiled a big beaming smile."
"ابتسموا بابتسامة واسعة مشرقة"
"They used their hands all over --
"لوّحوا بأيديهم في كل ناحية
I had to duck because their hands were coming at me."
فاضطررت إلى أن أتفادها، لأنها كادت أن تصطدم بي".
"They talk quickly with a little higher pitch."
"تحدثوا بسرعة مع طبقة صوت عالية قليلاً".
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
"They leaned in as if telling me a secret."
"مالوا نحوي كما لو أنهم يخبرونني بسر".
And then I said to them,
فقلت لهم:
"What happened to you as you listened to their passion?"
"ماذا حدث لكم عندما استمعتوا لشغفهم؟".
They said, "My eyes lit up.
قالوا: "عيني اشتعلت.
I smiled.
ابتسمت.
I leaned in."
انحنيت نحوهم".
When we tap into our passion,
فعندما نستفيد من شغفنا
we give ourselves the courage, in our own eyes, to speak up,
نعطي أنفسنا الشجاعة بأعيننا للتحدث،
but we also get the permission from others to speak up.
ولكننا نأخذ الأذن من الآخرين كذلك كي نتحدث.
Tapping into our passion even works when we come across as too weak.
تنجح الاستفادة من شغفنا حتى عندما يحدث وأن نكون ضعفاء جداً.
Both men and women get punished at work when they shed tears.
يُعاقب كل من الرجال والنساء في العمل عندما يذرفون الدموع.
But Lizzie Wolf has shown that when we frame our strong emotions as passion,
بيّنت ليزي وولف أن عندما نعبّر عن عواطفنا كشغف
the condemnation of our crying disappears for both men and women.
فإن الاستنكار من بكائنا يختفي عند كل من الرجال والنساء.
I want to end with a few words from my late father
أريد أختم بقليل من كلمات والدي الراحل،
that he spoke at my twin brother's wedding.
التي قالها في زفاف أخي التوأم.
Here's a picture of us.
هذه صورة لنا.
My dad was a psychologist like me,
كان والدي أخصائي نفسي مثلي،
but his real love and his real passion was cinema,
ولكن حبه وشغفه الحقيقي كان السينما؛
like my brother.
مثل أخي.
And so he wrote a speech for my brother's wedding
فكتب خطاباً لزواج أخي
about the roles we play in the human comedy.
عن الأدوار التي نلعبها في الكوميديا البشرية.
And he said, "The lighter your touch,
وقال: "كل ما كانت لمستك أخف،
the better you become at improving and enriching your performance.
كلما كنت أفضل في تحسين أدائك وإثراءه.
Those who embrace their roles and work to improve their performance
وأن أؤلئك الذين احتضنوا أدوارهم وعملوا على تحسين أدائهم
grow, change and expand the self.
نموا وتغيروا ووسّعوا ذاتهم.
Play it well,
إلعب دورك جيداً،
and your days will be mostly joyful."
وستكون معظم أيامك مُفرحة".
What my dad was saying
ما كان والدي يريد قوله،
is that we've all been assigned ranges and roles in this world.
هو أننا خصصنا نطاقات وأدوار في هذا العالم.
But he was also saying the essence of this talk:
ولكن كان يقول أيضاً أن جوهر هذا الحديث:
those roles and ranges are constantly expanding and evolving.
تتوسع هذه الأدوار والنطاقات وتتطور باستمرار.
So when a scene calls for it,
لذا عندما يستدعيها مشهد ما،
be a ferocious mama bear
كُن أم دب متوحش،
and a humble advice seeker.
وطالب نصيحة متواضع.
Have excellent evidence and strong allies.
ولتكن لديك براهين ممتازة وحلفاء أقوياء.
Be a passionate perspective taker.
وكُن متبني وجهة نظرٍ شغوف.
And if you use those tools --
فإذا استخدمتم هذه الأدوات
and each and every one of you can use these tools --
-يستطيع كل واحد منكم استخدام هذه الأدوات-
you will expand your range of acceptable behavior,
ستوسعون نطاقات سلوككم المقبولة
and your days will be mostly joyful.
وستكون معظم أيامكم مُفرحة.
Thank you.
شكراً لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)